Grace Duan

An experienced data scientist and statistician with more than 5 years training with a master's degree of Management in Artificial Intelligence possessing a solid theoretical and practical knowledge of statistics, machine learning, and data science for solving real world problems.



duanqiuying888@gmail.com



6476299077



Toronto

EDUCATION

Master of Management in Artificial Intelligence Schulich Business School

09/2020 - 08/2021

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Actuarial Science and Economics
University of Toronto

09/2015 - 06/2019

SKILLS

Data Science Toolkits: Python, SQL, R, Pandas, Numpy, sk-learn, Spark, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Tableau

Data Science Techniques: A/B testing, Experiment Design

Machine Learning Techniques: CNN, NLP, Regressions, SVM, Clustering, Classification

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Loblaw, ON

12/2021 - Present

Tasks/Achievements

- Converted supply chain problems such as out of stock and store order predictions into statistical and machine learning models and achieved accuracy increase by up to 15% and 18%.
- Created business intelligence dashboard for both business partners and data science team to help monitoring solution results and increased the model adoption rate by 20%.
- Collaborated with diverse teams to get data science models into production and led to an ROI improvement of 15% on supply chain optimization spend over the last 13 months.

Data Scientist ICEIBA, Remote, UK

01/2021 - 07/2021

Tasks/Achievements

- Built and fine-tuned VGG-16 CNN model in Keras for document image classification such as contracts, letters, emails along with intra-domain transfer learning and achieved 92.21% accuracy rate.
- Used Regular expression, spaCy, LexNLP to extract specific facts such as named entities, dates, currencies from classified documents and transformed them into structured data as the input of the legal analysis model.
- Helped increase the work efficiency of the company such that 100,000 more businesses can be accommodated with their commercial disputes and litigations worth \$1B in the recovery value during the next five years.

Industry Analyst Synced Technology Consulting Inc, Toronto, ON

07/2020 - 10/2020

Tasks/Achievements

- Developed both industry-specific and general market analysis to deliver insights regarding assigned machine intelligence fields such as Machine Learning, Neural Network, Computer Vision, Nature Language Process, and Robotics.
- Collected data on the machine intelligence industry and consolidated information into actionable items, insight articles, and industry research reports.
- Helped the launch of the 2020 Synced Machine Intelligence Awards which have become the largest and most authoritative annual awards platform in the Chinese AI industry.

SCHOOL PROJECTS

Using AI to Better Predict Airbnb Listing Prices

- Tackled the price-setting problem of airbnb by identifying an automated method to best estimate a suggested booking price for hosts that will maximize their earnings.
- Applied Random Forests model and Gridsearch, Recursive feature elimination, Forward Selection method, and PCA to increase the accuracy of the model prediction.
- Identified tasks, established plan for the team to reach their assigned goal and lead group meetings.

Clinic Relational Operational Database Design

- Prepared and converted conceptual design into a logical data model including ER diagram, relations, and metadata table.
- □ Implemented the design in PostgreSQL using Structured Query Language on database server.
- Responsible for making a project schedule for the group by creating milestones and sprints.